ILR School Labor Economics Department Records /4307
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Student financial aid and visa files, LE reserve readings (Box 15)
  - LE 340 Readings Not in Use, 1997-2001 (Box 15, Folder 44)
  - Kahn ILRCB 603 - scanned (Folder 1 of 2), 1986-1992 (Box 15, Folder 45)
  - Kahn ILRCB 603 - scanned (Folder 2 of 2), 1988-1993 (Box 15, Folder 46)
  - Docs. Relating to Affirmative Action, 1989-2000 (Box 15, Folder 47)
  - Docs. Relating to Medical Care + Discrimination HH-OO, 1992-1996 (Box 15, Folder 48)
  - Special Mailboxes E-mail, 2000 (Box 15, Folder 49)
  - Docs. Relating to Insurance, 1995-2000 (Box 15, Folder 50)
  - Docs. Related to Gender, Employment, Workers, 2000-2002 (Box 15, Folder 51)
  - Docs. Relating to Economics + Unemployment, 1985-1995 (Box 15, Folder 52)
  - Docs. Related to Labor Market, 2003 (Box 15, Folder 53)
  - Card: Fran Blau 265 (found loose in box) (Box 15, Folder 54)
- LE reserve readings, 1992-2003 (Box 16)
  - Empirical Strategies in Labor Economics, 1999 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - "Careers In Organizations: Theory and Evidence", 1999 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - "Executive Compensation", 1999 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - "Minimum Wages, Employment, and the Distribution of Income", 1999 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - "Gender Differences in Pay", 2000 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - "Symposium on Primary and Secondary Education", 1996 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - "Why Do So Many Young American Men Commit Crimes and What Might We Do About It?", 1996 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Institutional Changes and Rising Wage Inequality: Is There a Linkage?", 1997 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - "Job Displacement", 1998 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - "Distinguished Lecture on Economics in Government- Fighting Poverty: Lessons from Recent U.S. History", 2000 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - "Continuous vs. Episodic Change", 1991 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - "Strategic Bargaining Models and Interpretation of Strike Data", 1989 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - "An Analysis of the Use of Accounting and Market Measures of Performance in Executive Comparison Contracts", 1988 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - "Black Economic Progress After Myrdal", 1989 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Wage Inequality and the Rise in Returns to Skill, 1993 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - "The Role of Pre-Market Factors in the Black-White Wage Gap", 1996 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - "Wage Inequality and Family Labor Supply", 1997 (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - "Wages, Productivity and Worker Characteristics", 1999 (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - "The Family Gap for Young Women in the United States and Britain: Can Maternity Leave Make A Difference?", 1998 (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - "Job Stability in the United States", 1997 (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - "The Intergenerational Transmission of "Intelligence: Down the Slippery Slopes of the Bell Curve", 1999 (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - "How Much Do Immigration and Trade Affect Labor Market Outcomes?", 1997 (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - "The Change Face of Job Loss in the United States 1981-1995, 1997 (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - "New Developments in Models of Search in the Labor Market, 1999 (Box 16, Folder 24)
  - Mobility and Stability", 1999 (Box 16, Folder 25)
  - "The Analysis of Labor Markets Using Matched Employer Employee Data, 1999 (Box 16, Folder 26)
  - "Firm Size and Wages", 1999 (Box 16, Folder 27)
  - "Rising Wage Inequalities and the U.S. Gender Gap", 2001 (Box 16, Folder 28)
  - "Job Matching and the Theory of Turnover", 1996 (Box 16, Folder 29)
  - "Why Is There Mandatory Retirement?", 1996 (Box 16, Folder 30)
  - "Family Investments in Human Capital: Earnings of Women", 1974 (Box 16, Folder 31)
  - The Economics of Legal Conflicts, 1973 (Box 16, Folder 32)
  - "Does School Quality Matter?", 1992 (Box 16, Folder 33)
  - "Optimal Incentive Contracts", 1992 (Box 16, Folder 34)
  - The Effect of Wage Bargains on the Stock Market Value of the Firm, 1989 (Box 16, Folder 35)
  - "Job Matching", 1979 (Box 16, Folder 36)
  - Course in Microeconomic Theory, 1990 (Box 16, Folder 37)
  - "Tournament Mobility", 1979 (Box 16, Folder 38)
  - "The Effect of Wage Bargains", 1989 (Box 16, Folder 39)
  - "Managerial Task Assignment and Promotions", 1988 (Box 16, Folder 40)
  - "Natural + Quasi - Experiments in Economics:, 1995 (Box 16, Folder 41)
  - "Gross Worker and Job Flows in Europe", 1993 (Box 16, Folder 42)
  - "Searching for the Effect of Immigration on the Labor Market", 1996 (Box 16, Folder 43)
  - "Black-White Earnings Over 1970s and 1980s: Gender Differences in Trends", 1992 (Box 16, Folder 44)
  - "The Growing Importance of Cognitive Skills in Wage Determination", 1995 (Box 16, Folder 45)
  - Wealth Effects and Earnings Premium for Job Hazards", 1978 (Box 16, Folder 46)
  - "Does Compulsory School Attendance Affect Schooling and Earnings?", 1991 (Box 16, Folder 47)
  - "Decline of Male Labor Market Participant: The Role of Declining Market Opportunities", 1992 (Box 16, Folder 48)
  - "Changes in Relative Wages, 1963-1987", 1992 (Box 16, Folder 49)
  - "How Computers Have Changed the Wage Structure", 1993 (Box 16, Folder 50)
  - "Effect of Sibling Composition on Women's Education and Earnings", 1994 (Box 16, Folder 51)
  - "Natural and Quasi-Experiments in Economics", 1995 (Box 16, Folder 52)
  - "Labor Market Institutions and the Distribution of Wages, 1973-1992: A Semiparametric Approach", 1996 (Box 16, Folder 53)
  - "The Pure Theory of the Guaranteed Annual Wage Contract, 1946 (Box 16, Folder 54)
  - "The Impact of the Earned Income Tax Credit and Social Policy Reforms on Work, Marriage, and Living Arrangements, 2000 (Box 16, Folder 55)
  - "Racial Test Score Differences as Evidence of Reverse Discrimination: Less Than Meets the Eye, 1999 (Box 16, Folder 56)
  - "What Does Affirmative Action Do?", 2000 (Box 16, Folder 57)
  - "The Impact of Federal Civil Rights Policy on Black Economic Progress: Evidence from the Equal Opportunity Act of 1972, 1998 (Box 16, Folder 58)
  - "The Wage Effects of Sexual Orientation Discrimination", 1995 (Box 16, Folder 59)
  - "The Impact of the Mariel Boatlift", 1990 (Box 16, Folder 60)
  - The Incentive For Working Hard, 2000 (Box 16, Folder 61)
  - Changes In Job Stability and Job Security, 2000 (Box 16, Folder 62)
  - Annales D' Economie Et De Statistique No 55-56 1999 "Lillard - Job Turnover" (Box 16, Folder 63)
    Some Writing in French
  - Diff. JSTOR Articles Related to Affirmative Action, Education and Medical Care/ Healthcare, 1989-1994 (Box 16, Folder 64)
  - "Cohort Effects and Returns to Seniority in France", 1996 (Box 16, Folder 65)
    Some Text in French
  - "Private Discrimination and Social Intervention in Competitive Labor Markets", 1983 (Box 16, Folder 66)
  - Discrimination: Empirical Evidence from the United States", 1987 (Box 16, Folder 67)
  - "Self-Selection and the Earnings of Immigrants", 1987 (Box 16, Folder 68)
  - "Strikes and Holdouts in Wage Bargaining", 1992 (Box 16, Folder 69)
  - "Changes in the Structure of Wages in the 1980's", 1992 (Box 16, Folder 70)
  - "Will Affirmative -Action Policies Eliminate Negative Stereotypes?", 1993 (Box 16, Folder 71)
  - "Beauty and the Labor Market", 1994 (Box 16, Folder 72)
  - Estimates of the Economic Return to Schooling from a New Sample of Twins, 1994 (Box 16, Folder 73)
  - "Technology, Human Capital, and the Wage Structure", 1996 (Box 16, Folder 74)
  - "Exploring the "Resent Through the Past": Career and Family Across the Lost Century, 1997 (Box 16, Folder 75)
  - "The Role of the Family in Immigrants' Labor-Market Activity: An Evaluation of Alternative Explanations", 1997 (Box 16, Folder 76)
  - The Wage Structure: Occupational Wage Differences (Box 16, Folder 77)
  - Ch. 1-3 Regulating the Poor: The Functions of Public Welfare (Box 16, Folder 78)
  - Inequality, Growth and Investment, 1999 (Box 16, Folder 79)
  - The Effect of Wage Bargains on the Stock Market Value of the Firm, 1998 (Box 16, Folder 80)
  - NBER Working Paper Abowd and Farber, "Product Market Comp", 1990 (Box 16, Folder 81)
  - NBER Working Paper Abowd and Farber, "Product Market Comp", 1990 (Box 16, Folder 82)
  - Professor Blau- Student Papers, 2003 (Box 16, Folder 83)
  - Examine Booklets and Questions, 2003 (Box 16, Folder 84)
  - Papers For 441, 2003 (Box 16, Folder 85)
- Abowd course material (Box 17)
  - Abowd ILR 345 Spring 1994 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - ILR 740 (Folder 1 of 2), 1990 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - ILR 740 (Folder 2 of 2), 1990-1996 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Grad Labor Spring 1997 Abowd/Blau (missing some from early in the semester) (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - ILR 345 Corporate Fin 594 Abowd, 1994 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - 588 Packet ?, 1992 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - ILRLE 240 Econ 341, 1994 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Abowd ILR 240 Flat Originals, 1989 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - ILR 345 1993 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - ILR 345 Transparencies Spring 1991 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    Contains transparencies
  - 1990 ILR 345 Lecture Notes (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - 1991 ILR 345 Lecture Notes (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - ILR 345 Old Quizzes Finals 1988,1989,1990,1991,1993,1994, 1988-1994 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - 1988-1994 (Box 17, Folder 14)
- CUSS materials (duplicates, needs weeding_ (Box 18)
  - Fall 2001 CUSSS Week 2 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Fall 2001 CUSSS Week 3, 1998-2001 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Fall 2001 CUSSS Week 4 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Fall 2001 CUSSS Week 5 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Fall 2001 CUSSS Week 6 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Fall 2001 CUSSS Week 7 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Fall 2001 CUSSS Week 8, 2000-2001 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Fall 2001 CUSSS Week 9, 1997-2001 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Fall 2001 CUSSS Week 11 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Fall 2001 CUSSS Week 12 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Fall 2001 CUSSS Week 13 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Spring 2002 CUSS Week 1, 2001-2002 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Spring 2002 Week 2 CUSS (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Spring 2002 CUSSS Week 3 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Spring 2002 Week 4 CUSSS (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Spring 2002 Week 5 CUSSS (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Spring 2006 Week 6 CUSSS, 1998-2002 (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Spring 2002 Week 8 CUSSS (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Spring 2002 Week 9 CUSSS (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Spring 2002 CUSSS Week 10, 2001-2002 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Spring 2002 Week 13 CUSSS (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - Spring 2002 Week 14 CUSSS, 2001-2002 (Box 18, Folder 22)
- old printed account statements (Box 19)
  - 527 Blau, Francine, 1993-1998 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Blau, Francine (Folder 1 of 2), 1992-2000 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Blau, Francine (Folder 2 of 2), 1995-2001 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Abowd, John (Folder 1 of 2), 1994-2002 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Abowd, John (Folder 2 of 2), 1995-1999 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Jakubson, George, 1996-1997 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Department Accounts, 1996-2001 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - ILMP, 1993-2000 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Cornell University Transaction Statements (Folder 1 of 2), 1997-2002 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Cornell University Transaction Statements (Folder 2of 2), 1995-2002 (Box 19, Folder 10)
- Blau - Director of Research Material (Box 20)
  - Faculty Research Manual, 1997-1998 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Expert Director, Correspondence Regarding Grant Apps + Report + Docs. Related to Workers' Comp. Board and Cornell Univ., 1997- 1998 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - School of Industrial and Labor Relations Cornell University Expert Directory 1999 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Abowd, John, 1990-1996 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Aronson, R., 1973-1982 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Bacarach, 1995-1998 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Bartholomew, Richard, 1996 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Bishop, John, 1986-1992 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Blau, Francine, 1995-1998 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Boudreau, John, 1982-1987 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Boyer, George, 1983-1996 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Bretz, Robert, 1990 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Briggs, Vernon, 1978-1990 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Bunge, John, 1995-1998 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Clark, G., 1974-1979 (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Cook, Alice, 1974-1986 (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Cook, Maria, 1995-1997 (Box 20, Folder 17)
- Blau - Director of Research Material (Box 21)
  - Daniel, C., 1973-1990 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - DeVault, Ileen, 1987-1990 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - DiCiccio, Thomas J., 1998 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Donovan, R., 1973-1976 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Driscoll, Eilene (et. al), 1980-1987 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Dyer, L., 1979-1982 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Eastman, D., 1973-1974 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Farley, J., 1977-1978 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Frank, W., 1973 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Gasser, Linda, 1991-1997 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Barry Gerhart, 1986 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Gold, Michael, 1977-1997 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Gray, Lois, 1976-1986 (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Gross, J., 1979-1988 (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Gruenfeld, L., 1980-1994 (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Hadi, Ali, 1989-1998 (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - Halpern, Jennifer, 1994 (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - Hammer, T., 1979-1990 (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - Hebdon, Robert, 1995 (Box 21, Folder 19)
  - Julian, R., 1974 (Box 21, Folder 20)
  - Katz, Harry, 1985-1997 (Box 21, Folder 21)
  - Korman, A.G., 1974-1986 (Box 21, Folder 22)
  - Kuruvilla, Sarosh, 1990 (Box 21, Folder 23)
  - Lawler, Ed, 1995-1996 (Box 21, Folder 24)
  - Lieberwirtz, Risa, 1986 (Box 21, Folder 25)
- Blau - Director of Research Material (Box 22)
  - Benjamin Miller Award, 1999-2000 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Benjamin Miller Fund, 1995-1999 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Benjamin Miller Scholarship Award, 1994-1995 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Benjamin Miller Apps, 1991 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Pierce Memorial Fund, 1997 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Noteworthy Books in Industrial Relations and Labor Economics, 1997 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Director of Research's Responsibilities, 1998 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Cornell University Foundation Relations, 1999 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Funding Opportunities Announced via ILR FAC-L@cornell.edu, 1997 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Application for Research Assistance (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Request for Research Funds ( faculty form) (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Faculty Research Requests, 1997-2000 (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Request for CISER 4381 Supplemental Computing Resources, 1993 (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Request for Approval of Page Charges (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Form 10 Internal Academic Approval of Sponsored Programs (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - OSP Newsletter, 1997 (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - OSP Reports on Proposals (Grants), 1995-1998 (Box 22, Folder 17)
    Awarded and Submissions Pending
  - Updates Division of the Controller, 1996-1997 (Box 22, Folder 18)
  - Research Manual, 1993-1994 (Box 22, Folder 19)
  - ILR Review, 1999 (Box 22, Folder 20)
  - Associate Editor ILR Review, 1995 (Box 22, Folder 21)
  - Planning Committee, 1987 (Box 22, Folder 22)
  - Labor Economics Recruiting, 1987 (Box 22, Folder 23)
- Misc. Labor Economics files (Box 23)
  - Form 10 Internal Academic Approval of Sponsored Programs, 1996 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Freshman Colloquium, 1993 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Graduate Committee, 1984 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Robert M. Hutchens VITA, 1994 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Annual Reports Pre-1990, 1981 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Cornell Abroad Program, 1998 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Cornell Presidential Research Scholars Program, 2000 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Faculty order sheet for Textbooks and Supplies, 1995 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Annual Faculty Report, 1995 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Manuscript Appraisal, 1999 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - ILRLE 642, 2005 (Box 23, Folder 11)
    Economics of the Welfare State
  - IRLE745 Serminar in Labor Econ II, 2005 (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - ILRLE 746 Seminar in Labor Economics III, 2000 (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - ILR 441 Hutchens (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - ILR 642 Economy of the Welfare State (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - ILR 745 Hutchens, 1998 (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - Hutchens Copies of forms sent to OSS, 2014 (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - Alumni Association ILR, 2005 (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - Fogel Visit 10/2004 (Box 23, Folder 19)
  - ILRLE240 (Box 23, Folder 20)
    Economic Wages & Employment
  - ILRLE 441, 2005 (Box 23, Folder 21)
    Income Distribution
  - ILRLE 445, 2000 (Box 23, Folder 22)
    Women in the Economy